So here's what I'll suggest is my favorite ordering, is we're going to first
这是我要推荐的我最喜欢的顺序 首先我们先写一个
write a stub, daysInMonth, that will take a year and a month and return always
daysInMonth 的雏形 它将输入一个年份和月份 并总是返回 30
30, which certainly not correct. Then we'll modify our nextDay routine to use
这当然不正确 之后我们将修改 nextDay 函数
that stub, and then, right away, we'll test it. At this point, we won't have
来使用这个雏形 然后立刻对它进行测试
done anything that will actually change the outputs from what we were getting
截止到此时 我们还没有真正改变之前获得的输出
before if things are correct. But we're now restructure the code in a way that
如果测试是正确的话 但是我们现在正在重新构建代码
all we have to do is improve daysInMonth. And then we've got the correct answer.
我们所要做的就是改进 daysInMonth 函数 然后我们将会得到正确的答案
The next thing we'll do is modify daysInMonth to be correct, except for leap
下一件要做的 是将 daysInMonth 在不考虑闰年的情况下修改正确
years. I'm putting off leap years as long as I can because I think leap years
我会把考虑闰年尽量推迟 因为闰年真的很烦
are really annoying. But there are also a complexity that only comes up
但是这种复杂性也只是偶尔出现
occasionally. And we can have really close to a correct answer and know that
我们可以先得到一个非常接近正确的答案 并且知道
we've got all the structure of the code and everything in good place, putting
我们已经获得了所有的代码结构 一切都在合适的位置
that off. So, I'll do that. Then I think it's a good idea to test again. So
所以我将推迟考虑闰年 然后我认为再次测试是个好主意
we're going to do the testing again in step five, and it would have been
因此我们将在第五步再次测试 在这里
perfectly okay to do the testing using daysInMonth. I think it's easier to do it
用 daysInMonth 来测试当然是完全没有问题的 但是我认为一个更简单的方法是
using nextDay, since I can just keep rerunning the same tests that I did for
用 nextDay 因为我们只需要再运行一次 和步骤3一样的测试就可以了
step three. Now, I've got to the point where I really can't put off leap years
现在我们就到了需要考虑闰年的时候了
any longer, so I'm going to do the leap years next, and I'll write a helper
所以接下来要解决闰年的问题 我将先写一个
procedure isLeapYear. That's step 6. And I'm going to test that separately.
辅助函数 isLeapYear 这是步骤6 之后我将对它进行单独测试
That's another step that you could argue, well, I could test that using
这是另一个你可能会有异议的步骤 会想也可以用
daysInMonth or using nextDay. In this case isLeapYear, they're enough special
daysInMonth 或者 nextDay 来测试 但是 isLeapYear 有点特别
cases that it makes more sense to test that separately. Okay, and after I've
把它拿来单独测试会更加有意义 好的 完成这个之后
done that I should have a fully correct solution. I could test it separately,
就有了一个完整的解决方案了 可以再分开测试它一下
but I'm pretty confident in the rest of my code at this point. I'm going to jump
但是我现在对我剩下的代码很有信心 我将直接跳到
right ahead to step K and run all the test cases. So this is order I'd
步骤 K 来运行所有的测试用例 这就是我推荐的顺序了
recommend, but there's plenty of other orders that make sense. One thing that
但是当然还有很多其他顺序也是对的 其中一个就是
would certainly make sense would be to move the leap year stuff to the
你可以把闰年的程序放到最开始去
beginning. If you like leap years, and don't want to put that off, easy to do
如果你喜欢闰年 也不想把它推迟到后面再做的话
that separately first. The other thing that could happen is instead of using the
那就可以先单独把它弄完 另一件可能会发生的事是
nextDay test, use the daysInMonth test. That would be perfectly reasonable as
用了 daysInMonth 来测试 而不是 nextDay 这也是完全没问题的
well. So there are lots of correct answers to this question. The property that
所以对于这个问题 这里有很多正确的答案
they should all have, all the correct answers, is that you're writing small bits
这些所有正确答案共同的特点是 不停地写一点点代码
of code that you can test independently as you go. You don't want to be writing
然后再对其进行独立测试 而不是写一大堆代码
a lot of code and not being able to test it. That's one of the most important
而不能对它进行测试 在开发者要学习的事情中
things to learn as a developer is to think of ways to structure a code, to
最重要的一件是 思考结构化代码的方法
organize the way you build code, so you're able to do meaningful tests as you go
去组织你构建代码的方法 这样你就能够在写的时候 进行有意义的测试
and see the code incrementally get closer to the solution that you need for
并且看着代码一步步越来越接近你需要的正确答案
that. As you get more confident as a programmer, you might skip some of these
当你对作为一个程序员更加有自信的时候 你可能会跳过一些步骤
steps. But part of my motivation in asking this question is, when I tried to
但是我问这个问题的部分动机是
solve this problem myself, I had a bug in my solution, because I didn't do these
当我自己做这个问题的时候 我的解答出现了一个 bug 这是因为
steps carefully enough. And I've tried running all the test cases and they all
我没有足够仔细地按照步骤来做 当我试着运行所有测试时
failed. And, debugging it took a lot longer than if I'd followed this pattern.
它们都失败了 比起按照步骤做 调试多花了很多时间
What I'm going to encourage you to do as you develop your solution, is to write
当你在解答时 我要鼓励你去做的是
code to run all these tests as part of your solution. And, what I hope will
作为你解答的一部分 写代码来运行所有测试 之后我期盼的是
happen, if you do these steps, testing as you go. When you finally get to step
如果你进行了所有步骤 也都测试完了 当你最后到达步骤 K 时
K, and run it on all the test cases, it will magically all work correctly the
把程序在所有测试用例上运行时 它将神奇般地一次就运行正确了
first time. Except, it won't be magic. It'll be the result of building things in
当然这并不是什么魔法 这只是系统地以及小心地
a systematic and careful way.
解决问题的自然结果